Hello. Welcome back. This week,
the first thing we'll do
is show you a number of
case studies of effective
convolutional neural networks.
Why look at case studies?
Last week we learned about
the basic building blocks,
such as convolutional
layers, pooling layers,
and fully connected
layers of convnet.
It turns out the past few years
of computer vision research
has been on how to
put together these basic
building blocks to
form effective convolutional
neural networks.
One of the best ways
for user gain intuition
yourself is to see some
of these examples.
I think just as many of
you may have learned
to write code by reading
other people's codes,
I think that a good way to gain
intuition and how the
build confidence is
to read or to see other examples
of effective confidence.
It turns out that a
neural network
architecture that works
well on one computer
vision tasks
often works well on
other tasks as well,
such as maybe on your task.
If someone else's train
a neural network or has
figured out a neural
network architecture,
there's very good at recognizing
cats and dogs and people.
But you have a different
computer vision tasks like
maybe you're trying to
build a self-driving car,
you might well be able to take
someone else's neural
network architecture
and apply that to your problem.
Finally, after the
next few videos,
you'll be able to read some of
the research papers from the
field of computer vision,
and I hope that you might
find it satisfying as well.
You don't have to
do this as class
where you might
find it satisfying,
typically read some of
these several computer
vision research paper
and see yourself able
to understand them.
With that, let's get started.
As an outline for what we'll
do in the next few videos,
we'll first show you a
few classic networks.
LeNet-5 network which
came from, I guess,
in 1980s, AlexNet which
is often cited in
the VGG network.
These are examples of pretty
effective neural networks,
and you see ideas from
these papers that will
probably be useful for
your own work as well.
Then I want to show you
the ResNet or called
residual network.
You might have heard
that neural networks
and getting deeper and deeper,
the ResNet neural
network trained
a very deep 152 layer
neural network.
It has some very
interesting tricks,
interesting ideas how
they do that effectively.
Then finally, you also
see a case study of the
Inception neural network.
After seeing these
neural networks,
I think you have much
better intuition
about how to build
effective convolutional
neural networks.
Even if you end up not working
computer vision yourself,
you find a lot of the ideas
from some of these examples,
such as ResNet,
Inception network,
many of these ideas
are cross fertilizing,
are making their way
into other disciplines.
Even if you don't
end up building
computer vision
applications yourself,
I think you'll find
some of these ideas
very interesting and
helpful for your work.